const questions = [
  {
    question: "1. What is the capital of France?",
    options: ["Berlin", "Paris", "Rome", "Madrid"],
    answer: "Paris",
  },
  {
    question: "2. Which planet is known as the 'Red Planet'?",
    options: ["Venus", "Mars", "Jupiter", "Saturn"],
    answer: "Mars",
  },
  {
    question: "3. What is the largest mammal in the world?",
    options: ["Elephant", "Blue Whale", "Giraffe", "Hippopotamus"],
    answer: "Blue Whale",
  },
  {
    question: "4. Who wrote the play 'Romeo and Juliet'?",
    options: [
      "William Shakespeare",
      "George Orwell",
      "Mark Twain",
      "Charles Dickens",
    ],
    answer: "William Shakespeare",
  },
  {
    question: "5. What is the chemical symbol for water?",
    options: ["Wo", "Hy", "Wa", "H2O"],
    answer: "H2O",
  },
  {
    question: "6. Which country is famous for its tulips and windmills?",
    options: ["Germany", "France", "Netherlands", "Italy"],
    answer: "Netherlands",
  },
  {
    question: "7. What is the largest organ in the human body?",
    options: ["Brain", "Liver", "Skin", "Heart"],
    answer: "Skin",
  },
  {
    question: "8. Who painted the Mona Lisa?",
    options: [
      "Pablo Picasso",
      "Vincent van Gogh",
      "Leonardo da Vinci",
      "Michelangelo",
    ],
    answer: "Leonardo da Vinci",
  },
  {
    question: "9. What is the currency of Japan?",
    options: ["Yen", "Won", "Yuan", "Euro"],
    answer: "Yen",
  },
  {
    question:
      "10. Which gas do plants absorb from the atmosphere for photosynthesis?",
    options: ["Oxygen", "Carbon Dioxide", "Nitrogen", "Hydrogen"],
    answer: "Carbon Dioxide",
  },
];

export { questions };
